Guide to the International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers, Lodge 751E Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers, Lodge 751E records
1961-1991
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
5818
5818-001
International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers.$bLodge 751-E (Seattle, Wash.)
2 cubic ft 2 boxes
Records of the Association Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers, Lodge 751E which is comprised of skilled electronics workers at Boeing.
IAM 751-E is local lodge of the International Association of Machinists, District 751. Chartered by the District in 1961, the local's membership is comprised of skilled electronics workers at Boeing.
Financial and membership reports, meeting minutes, correspondence, rosters.
Records stored off site; advance notice required for use.
Open to all users.
Roy Wilkinson, Recording Secretary IAM 751-E, 2/18/2014.
International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers.$bAerospace Industrial District Lodge 751-E$vArchives; Labor$zWashington (State)$xHistory$vSources; Labor unions$zWashington (State)$xHistory$vSources; Labor movement$zWashington (State)$xHistory$vSources; Strikes and lockouts$zWashington (State)$xHistory$vSources; Machinists$xLabor unions$zWashington (State)$xHistory$vSources; Aerospace industries$xEmployees$xLabor unions$zWashington (State)$xHistory$vSources; Business correspondence; Minutes (Records); financial records; rosters; International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers.$bLodge 751-E (Seattle, Wash.)$vArchives; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington)
Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor Unions; Labor History
- CHARITABLE DONATIONS, 1979-1981; SERIES I (Box-folder 1/1-1/2)
  - City of Hope Charitable Donation, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Guiding Eyes Charitable Donation, 1979 (Box-folder 1/2)
- COMMUNICATIONS COMMITTEE MEETINGS AND ASSOCIATED CORRESPONDENCE, 1988-1991; SERIES II (Box-folder 1/3-1/29)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence: March-June, 1991 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence: February-April, 1991 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence: January-February, 1990 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence: February, 1991 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence: November, 1990 (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence: November, 1990 (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence: October, 1990 (Box-folder 1/10)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence, 1990 (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence: August, 1990 (Box-folder 1/12)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence: July [Includes bound copy of Grand Lodge IAMAW Financial Statement and Audit Report dated December 31, 1988], 1990 (Box-folder 1/13)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence: June, 1990 (Box-folder 1/14)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence: May, 1990 (Box-folder 1/15)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence: April, 1990 (Box-folder 1/16)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence: March, 1990 (Box-folder 1/17)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence: November, 1989 (Box-folder 1/18)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence: December, 1989 (Box-folder 1/19)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence: November, 1989 (Box-folder 1/20)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence: October, 1989 (Box-folder 1/21)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence: August, 1989 (Box-folder 1/22)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence: September, 1989 (Box-folder 1/23)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence: July, 1989 (Box-folder 1/24)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence: June, 1989 (Box-folder 1/25)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence: May [Includes bound summary of 1988 AFL-CIO convention proceedings], 1988-1989 (Box-folder 1/26)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence: February-April [Includes bound copy of Grand Lodge IAMAW Financial Statement and Audit Report dated June 30, 1988], 1988-1989 (Box-folder 1/27)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence: January, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 1/28)
  - Communications Committee Meeting Materials and Correspondence, 1990 (Box-folder 1/29)
- CONTRACTS, 1980-1989; SERIES III (Box-folder 1/30)
  - Contract Study Reports and Correspondence: 1980, 1986, 1989, 1980-1989 (Box-folder 1/30)
- IAM 751 DISTRICT COUNCIL, 1961-1992; SERIES IV (Box-folder 1/31-1/50)
  - General Council Information, 1961-1992; Subseries A (Box-folder 1/31-1/42)
    - Blank stationary: IAM Electronic Services Lodge 751-E, Undated (Box-folder 1/31)
    - Job Title Listing and District Council Member Information, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 1/32)
    - Blank District Meeting Attendance Sign-In Forms, Undated (Box-folder 1/33)
    - Local Lodge 751-E Officer Rosters, 1991 (Box-folder 1/34)
    - Local Lodge 751-E Officer Roster and Attendance Record, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 1/35)
    - Blank Local Lodge 751-E Attendance Record, 1989 (Box-folder 1/36)
    - Convention Delegates Information, 1980-1987 (Box-folder 1/37)
    - Local Lodge 751-E Secretary-Treasurer Materials, 1961-1975 (Box-folder 1/38)
    - Local Lodge 751-E Officer Rosters, 1967-1979 (Box-folder 1/39)
    - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Attendance, 1965 (Box-folder 1/40)
    - Blank Attendance Sign-In Forms, Undated (Box-folder 1/41)
    - Records Retention Guidelines, Undated (Box-folder 1/42)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1980; Subseries B (Box-folder 1/43-1/49)
    - Action Newsletter [Machinists Non-Partisan Political League], 1974-1979 (Box-folder 1/43)
    - Health Coalition [Washington Coalition for a National Health Program], 1975-1979 (Box-folder 1/44)
    - Local A, C, F Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 1/45)
    - District Correspondence [Includes Lodge 751's "Resolution Concerning the Domed Stadium and the Issues of the Forward Thrust Election" dated June 1, 1970], 1970-1979 (Box-folder 1/46)
    - Local Lodge 751-E Correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 1/47)
    - Local Lodge 751-E Correspondence, 1966 (Box-folder 1/48)
    - MNPL [Machinists Non-Partisan League] Achievement Certificate, 1989 (Box-folder 1/49)
  - Photograph, Undated; Subseries C (Box-folder 1/50)
    - Photograph of Local Lodge 751-E Officers Ernst Stewart, Ellery Lamb, and George Perry [8 x 10 Black and White; includes envelope with inscription], Undated (Box-folder 1/50)
- ELECTIONS INFORMATION, 1969-1988; SERIES V (Box-folder 1/51-1/57)
  - Election Information, 1974-1985 (Box-folder 1/51)
  - Election Information, 1984 (Box-folder 1/52)
  - Election Committee Reports, 1969-1983 (Box-folder 1/53)
  - Washington State Labor Council, AFL-CIO: Correspondence and Election Information, 1979 (Box-folder 1/54)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Elections, 1971 (Box-folder 1/55)
  - Blank Meeting Attendance and Election Registration Forms, Undated (Box-folder 1/56)
  - Election and Candidate Information, 1984-1988 (Box-folder 1/57)
- FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1968-2009; SERIES VI (Box-folder 1/58-2/10)
  - District Audits, 1968-1990; Subseries A (Box-folder 1/58-1/60)
    - District Audit, 1970-1975 (Box-folder 1/58)
    - Local Lodge 751-E Audit Reports, 1968-1986 (Box-folder 1/59)
    - Letter Regarding Audit Findings [Includes reference to questionable financial activity by some members], 1990 (Box-folder 1/60)
  - Expense Vouchers and Requests, 1970-1992; Subseries B (Box-folder 1/61-2/1)
    - Expense Vouchers and Financial Reports: January 1990, February 1991-June 1991, October-December 1991, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 1/61)
    - Delegate Expense Request, 1992 February 3 (Box-folder 1/62)
    - Expense Vouchers, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 1/63)
    - Expense Vouchers, 1990 (Box-folder 1/64)
    - Expense Vouchers, 1988 (Box-folder 1/65)
    - Expense Vouchers, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 1/66)
    - Expense Vouchers, 1982-1987 (Box-folder 1/67)
    - Expense Vouchers, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 1/68)
    - Expense Vouchers, 1983-1988 (Box-folder 1/69)
    - Expense Vouchers, 1971-1977 (Box-folder 1/70)
    - Expense Vouchers, 1970-1981 (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Monthly Financial and Membership Reports, 1968-2009; Subseries C (Box-folder 2/2-2/10)
    - Meeting and Finance Material, 2008-2009 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Monthly Financial and Membership Reports, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Monthly Financial and Membership Reports, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Monthly Financial and Membership Reports, 1988 (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Monthly Financial and Membership Reports, 1980-1987 (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Monthly Financial and Membership Reports, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Monthly Financial and Membership Reports, 1970-1979 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Monthly Financial and Membership Reports, 1970-1979 (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Monthly Financial and Membership Reports, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 2/10)
- GOVERNANCE, 1969-1988; SERIES VII (Box-folder 2/11-2/13)
  - District Bylaws, 1969-1988; Subseries A (Box-folder 2/11-2/12)
    - Local Lodge Bylaws, 1988 April 12 (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Bylaws Changes, 1969-1975 (Box-folder 2/12)
  - Constitution, 1969; Subseries B (Box-folder 2/13)
    - Bound copy of IAMA Constitution, 1969 (Box-folder 2/13)
- GRIEVANCES, 1974-1990; SERIES VIII (Box-folder 2/14-2/15)
  - Boeing Computer Services Grievance Materials, 1974-1984 (Box-folder 2/14)
  - Job Erosion Committee Materials, 1988 (Box-folder 2/15)
- IAM 751-E MEETING MINUTES, 1961-1991; SERIES IX (Box-folder 2/16-2/47)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Notes: 1991 April 3 (Box-folder 2/16)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1989 (Box-folder 2/17)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1990 (Box-folder 2/18)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes: 1990 [Includes general correspondence] (Box-folder 2/19)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1988 (Box-folder 2/20)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1987 (Box-folder 2/21)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1986 (Box-folder 2/22)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1985 (Box-folder 2/23)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1984 (Box-folder 2/24)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1983 (Box-folder 2/25)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1982 (Box-folder 2/26)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1981 (Box-folder 2/27)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes [Includes report from the Contract Negotiation Committee with regard to 1980 contract negotiations] (Box-folder 2/28)
  - Grand Lodge Executive Council Meeting Minutes [Includes bound copies of two Grand Lodge IAMAW Audit Reports dated December 31, 1970 and 1978], 1970-1979 (Box-folder 2/29)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1979 (Box-folder 2/30)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1975 (Box-folder 2/31)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1973 (Box-folder 2/32)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1972 (Box-folder 2/33)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1971 (Box-folder 2/34)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1970 (Box-folder 2/35)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 2/36)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes and Correspondence [Includes an undated report from IAMAW titled "A Report on Boeing Contract Proposal." It includes a copy of the proposed contract, which references dates from the early to mid-1960s.], 1969-1980 (Box-folder 2/37)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 2/38)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1967 (Box-folder 2/39)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1966 (Box-folder 2/40)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1965 (Box-folder 2/41)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1964 (Box-folder 2/42)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 2/43)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1962 (Box-folder 2/44)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1961 (Box-folder 2/45)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Minutes, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 2/46)
  - Local Lodge 751-E Meeting Materials, 1990 (Box-folder 2/47)
- STRIKES, 1990-1991; SERIES X (Box-folder 2/48-2/49)
  - Trial Report for Scabs 1989 Picket [Includes transcript of proceedings, ballots, and regular meeting minutes], 1990 (Box-folder 2/48)
  - 1989 Scab Trial, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 2/49)